# Jaehoon Jung

(631)838-1305 | hoon7589@gmail.com | https://jayjung98.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayjungnote/

#### **PROFILE**

Data Scientist who sees problems and makes decisions through data. Data scientists are necessary to have an attitude to solve everyday questions with data. I have the ability to define problems, find necessary data, analyze and solve them, and visualize and explain their conclusions. I studied basic coding and machine learning concepts through classes in school, and additionally, I personally studied machine learning through Python to improve coding skills. Also, through personal projects, I found a problem that I was interested in, experienced how to solve it, and developed my analytical thinking skills.

## **EDUCATION**

Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY

January 2019 – December 2022

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and Statistics

**Major GPA**: 3.31/4.00

Relevant courses: Data analysis, Data mining, Operation research, Mathematical statistics, Database design

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Python, R, SQL, Java, C++

Software and Integrated Development Environments (IDEs): Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Microsoft

Visual Studio, Google Colab, RStudio, Eclipse, MS Acess

**Languages:** English – proficient, Korean - native

#### **PROJECTS**

2022 Qatar World Cup Prediction: <a href="https://github.com/JayJung98/2022WorldCupWinner">https://github.com/JayJung98/2022WorldCupWinner</a>

- Experienced ranking prediction by using machine learning.
- Experienced the visualization of simulation results for people.

Roan and Repayment: <a href="https://jayjung98.github.io/project/Repayment/">https://jayjung98.github.io/project/Repayment/</a>

- Computed which features impact on whether the loan is repaid or not.
- Visualized the result and provided the interpretation of the resulting values.

Rossmann Store Sales: https://jayjung98.github.io/project/Rossmann/

- Computed and visualized important features.
- Computed the best prediction of this data.

Mobile Data Classification: <a href="https://jayjung98.github.io/project/performance/">https://jayjung98.github.io/project/performance/</a>

- Computed cross-validation-score of each data model.
- Compared and evaluated the performance of each the following models: logistic regression, decision tree classifier, random forest classifier, Ada boosting, and Gradient boosting decision tree.

**Soccer Player Analyzing:** https://jayjung98.github.io/project/FIFA-DATA/

- Interpreted players to scout from European league players and remove from team squad.
- Computed and visualized specific personal skills using computer software.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Army at Republic of Korea, Sergeant, Honorable discharged

Goseong, Kangwon-do

- Served in the general outpost at Go-Seong.
- Executed a mission to monitor and analyze the enemies.

*January* 2020 – *August* 2021

## **ACTIVITIES**

English Peer Tutoring for International Students, Member of Bridge Tutor

San Angelo, TX

• Provided fun student-led, language-learning environment.

*August 2017 – December 2018* San Angelo, TX

Korea Student Association, Member of Welfare

August 2017 – December 2018

• Provided opportunities to learn Korean culture and language.

• Hold K-Pop concert for San Angelo people.

Korean Life Media, Data Collector

Stony Brook, NY

• Executed collect and design data for the monthly radio broadcast. August 2019 – December 2019